<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <p>Besides graphs, another way we summarize data and compare sets of data is though numerical summaries. Below you will find two tables of numerical summaries of different datasets. Use these tables to answer the questions below. Answer all questions completely and include contextual information in your answers. Show or explain all of your work and include screen shots of any applets you use. </p>
        <p>Poverty, disease, hunger, climate change, war, existential risks, and inequality: The world faces many great and terrifying problems. It is these large problems that our work at Our World in Data focuses on. Our World in Data is a non-profit that has as its mission to make the knowledge on the big problems accessible and understandable. The information below is the annual percentage change in energy consumption from 1967 to 2020 for China and the United States. The numerical summaries of both datasets are in the tables below.</p>
        <p>China</p>
        <p><me>\begin{array}{|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|}
            \hline
            \text{ N } &amp;\text{ Min } &amp;\text{ Q1 } &amp;\text{ Median } &amp;\text{ Q3 } &amp;\text{ Max } &amp;\text{ Mean } &amp;\text{ St Dev } \\
            \hline
            \ {{n_1}} &amp; {{min_1}} &amp; {{q1_1}} &amp; {{med_1}} &amp; {{q3_1}} &amp; {{max_1}} &amp; {{mean_1}} &amp; {{stdev_1}} \\
            \hline
            \end{array}</me>
        </p>
        <p>United States</p>
        <p><me>\begin{array}{|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|}
            \hline
            \text{ N } &amp;\text{ Min } &amp;\text{ Q1 } &amp;\text{ Median } &amp;\text{ Q3 } &amp;\text{ Max } &amp;\text{ Mean } &amp;\text{ St Dev } \\
            \hline
            \ {{n_2}} &amp; {{min_2}} &amp; {{q1_2}} &amp; {{med_2}} &amp; {{q3_2}} &amp; {{max_2}} &amp; {{mean_2}} &amp; {{stdev_2}} \\
            \hline
            \end{array}</me>
        </p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the {{min_max}} that an annual percentage change could be in {{country_1}} and still be {{dir_1}} than {{percent_1}}<m>\%</m> of all the annual percentage changes in {{country_1}}?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>{{answer_1}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>The dataset for {{country_2}} has a quartile {{quar_2}} of {{change_2}}. Explain what this means in terms of the years in the dataset and their annual percentage changes in {{country_2}}.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>From 1967 to 2020 in {{country_2}}, {{percent_2}}<m>\%</m> of the annual percentage change in energy consumptions was {{change_2}}<m>\%</m> or less.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What would happen to the standard deviation of the dataset for China if an additional point was added at or {{dir_3}}? Why?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>{{answer_3}}, explanation needed</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Create boxplots for each of the numerical summaries given above. You may use the applet above or you may draw the boxplots by hand. Insert screenshots of pictures of both boxplots in your answer. Be sure to fully label your boxplots.</p></content>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Describe the shape of the distribution of annual percentage change in energy consumption in {{country_5}}. Use evidence from your boxplots from #4 to justify your answer.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>{{answer_5}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <!--<knowl>
        <content><p>Which of these datasets appears to be more skewed? Use evidence from your boxplots above to justify your answer.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The United States is more skewed</p></outtro>
    </knowl> -->
</knowl>
