<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <p>Besides graphs, another way we summarize data and compare sets of data is though numerical summaries. Below you will find two tables of numerical summaries of different datasets. Use these tables to answer the questions below. Answer all questions completely and include contextual information in your answers. Show or explain all of your work and include screen shots of any applets you use. </p>
        <p>Poverty, disease, hunger, climate change, war, existential risks, and inequality: The world faces many great and terrifying problems. It is these large problems that our work at Our World in Data focuses on. Our World in Data is a non-profit that has as its mission to make the knowledge on the big problems accessible and understandable. The information below is the annual percentage change in energy consumption for two countries. The numerical data for the last few years is in the tables below.</p>
        <p>Country A</p>
        <p><me>\begin{array}{|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|}
            \hline
            \ {{d1_2}} &amp; {{d2_2}} &amp; {{d3_2}} &amp; {{d4_2}} &amp; {{d5_2}} &amp; {{d6_2}} &amp; {{d7_2}} &amp; {{d8_2}}  &amp; {{d9_2}} &amp; {{d10_2}} \\
            \hline
            \end{array}</me>
        </p>
        <p>Country B</p>
        <p><me>\begin{array}{|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|c|}
            \hline
            \ {{d1}} &amp; {{d2}} &amp; {{d3}} &amp; {{d4}} &amp; {{d5}} &amp; {{d6}} &amp; {{d7}} &amp; {{d8}}  &amp; {{d9}} &amp; {{d10}} \\
            \hline
            \end{array}</me>
        </p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the mean and median of the percent change in energy for {{country_1}} ?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>mean={{ans1}},median={{ans1a}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <outtro></outtro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the variance and standard deviation of the annual percentage change  in {{country_1}} ?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>variance={{ans2}}, std={{ans2a}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p> looking at the data from {{country_1}} if {{data_info}}, what interval contains {{percent}} <m>%</m> of the data?</p></content>
        <outtro><p> between {{lower_bound}} and {{upper_bound}} </p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Describe the shape of the distribution of annual percentage change in energy consumption in {{country_2}} (hint: find the mean and median).</p></content>
        <outtro><p>{{skewness}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Which of these datasets appears to be more skewed? Use evidence from your boxplots above to justify your answer.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>Country A is more skewed</p></outtro>
    </knowl> 
</knowl>
