<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
      <p>
          A critical component to our understanding of statistics is being able to read and understand graphs. It is also critical that we be able to look at graphs and identify any flaws they might have. Be sure to answer ALL the questions.
      </p>
        <p>
            <image source="/assets/SLO3-A/212.png" description="Bar graph showing numbers of essential working in the pandemic and percent that were women, broken down by type of work."/>
        </p>
        <p>
           Figure 1: Essential Workers
        </p>
        <p>Below is a graph showing the distribution of the running lengths of a sample of 112 movies found on Hulu. </p>
        <p><image source="/assets/SLO3-B/212.png" description="Histogram showing the distribution of running length of movies"/></p>
        <p>Figure 2: Movie Run Times</p>
      <p>
          Use the graphs above to answer the questions. Make sure to show all of your work and put all answers into context of the data.
      </p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What type of graph is figure 1?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>A bar graph.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What percent of {{job_2}} workers were women? What information in the graph tells you this answer?</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{answer_2}}</m>%. The number inside the bars.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What does the <m>{{total_3}}</m> in the line that says "{{job_3}}" mean in the context of the information presented by figure 1?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>That means there were a total of <m>{{total_3}}</m> people working as {{job_3}} workers</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>According to figure 1, approximately how many women worked as {{job_4}}? Show all your work and give your answers in complete sentences.</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>.{{answer_4p}}</m> x <m>{{answer_4t}}</m> = <m>{{answer_4}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What type of graph is figure 2?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>A histogram.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Describe the shape of the distribution of running times of the sample of movies from Hulu (figure 2). Explain your answer.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The distribution is skewed right. (Can also argue that it is symmetrical with outliers)</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>In Figure 2, what does the bar with the {{number_2}} above it represent? </p></content>
        <outtro><p>Out of the 110 movies in the data set, {{number_2}} of them had running length between {{answer_2_1}}.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p> Using figure 2, what percentage of movies in the sample had a running length between <m>{{minutes_3a}}</m> and <m>{{minutes_3b}}</m> minutes? Show all your work including anything plugged into a calculator. Provide your final answer in a full sentence with the appropriate context.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>(<m>{{answer_3a}}</m> + <m>{{answer_3b}}</m> + <m>{{answer_3c}}</m>) / 112 = <m>{{answer_3}}</m><m>\%</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
</knowl>
