<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
    <p>Directions:</p>
    <p>Show all your calculations, including anything you plug into a calculator. Answers should be given in complete sentences and in the context of the situation.</p>
    <p><em>Scenario:</em></p>
     <p>
        One of the things that students who want to go to Medical School or Law School have to do is take a standardized test. The MCAT is required for admission to Medical school, the LSAT is required for admission to law school. These tests are called “standardized” because they are given in the same manner to all test takers and are graded in the same manner. Additionally, the scores designed to be normally distributed.
       </p>
    <p>
        In 2019, a sample of {{n1}} MCAT exams had a mean score of {{mean1}} and a standard deviation of {{STD1}} and a smaple of {{n2}} LSAT exams had a mean of {{mean2}} with a standard deviation of {{STD2}}. Please use this information to answer the questions below.
        </p>
        

     </intro>
    <knowl>

    <intro>
        <p> We want to construct a {{CL}} \% Confidence interval about the mean score on the {{ind_1}}. {{zort}} </p>
    </intro>
    
    <knowl>
        <content><p> What is the critical value for the first confidence interval?  </p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{CV}}</m> </p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
            <content><p>What is the standard error for the first confidence interval</p></content>
            <outtro><p><m>{{SE}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Construct and interpret the confidence interval about the mean scores for the {{ind_1}} using either the above information or Minitab </p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>({{CI_L}},{{CI_U}})</m>  </p></outtro>
    </knowl>

    </knowl>
     <knowl>
        <content><p>If  we want to construct a {{CL3}} \% confidence interval for the mean score on the {{ind_1}} with a margin of error of {{ME}}, what is the minimum sample size needed?</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{ans_4}}</m> {{ind_2}} </p></outtro>
    </knowl>

   <!-- 
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Construct and interpret a {{CL2}} \% confidence interval for the difference between the mean scores for the {{ind_1}} and the {{ind_2}}.</p> </content>
        <outtro><p><m>({{LB}},{{UB}})</m> grams </p></outtro>

    </knowl>
--> 

        

</knowl>




