<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
    <p>Directions:</p>
    <p>Show all your calculations, including anything you plug into a calculator. Answers should be given in complete sentences and in the context of the situation.</p>
    <p><em>Scenario:</em></p>
    <p>
        In many areas of medicine, there are different measurements used to define “healthy” based on gender, age, and race. One such measurement is bone density. Bone density is important, because as we age, bone density can decrease. If it decreases too much, we become at much higher risk of breaking bones.
       </p>
    <p>
        For example, for people aged 25, White Women have a mean bone density of 955 with a standard deviation of 123 and Black Women have a mean bone density of 1040 with a standard deviation of 135. Please use this information to answer the questions below.
        </p>
     </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the z-score for a someone whose bone density is <m>{{dep_1}}</m> and is a {{ind_1}}?</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{answer_1}}</m> </p></outtro></knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>{{statement2}}</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{answer_2}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>{{statement3}}</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{answer_3}}</m> </p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>In a sample of 100 {{ind_4}}, what proportion of sample mean bone densities are between <m>{{dep_3}}</m> and <m>{{dep_4}}</m>?</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>{{answer_4}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Diane is a 25 year old woman whose bone density is <m>{{dep_5}}</m>. Which group is bigger - the proportion of Black women who have a bone density lower than Diane or the proportion of White women who have a bone density higher than Diane? Justify your answer using a statistical analysis.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>Proportion of Black women with lower bone density = <m>{{answer_5a}}</m> | Proportion of White women higher bone density = <m>{{answer_5b}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
</knowl>